Chaim Halbert

Phoenix, AZ 85016, local to area or remote github.com/chaimleib — linkedin.com/in/chaim-halbert — chaim.leib.halbert@gmail.com

GOALS

- · Backend, full-stack, cloud, or embedded systems engineering
- · Protect privacy, empower the customer

SKILLS

Coding: More than 20 years of experience; first website at age 11. Recent work experience in *Go*, *C#*, *JavaScript/Node.js*, *TypeScript*, *Java*, *Python*, *MySQL*, *bash*, *zsh*, *ash and dash*; less recent work in *Perl*, *PHP*, *Ruby*, *Visual Basic .Net*, *ladder logic*, *PLC structured text*, *LISP*. Education and personal project experience in *most of these and also C*, *C++*, *Objective-C*, *Swift*, *awk*, *Scheme*, *Matlab/Octave*, *Verilog*. Can write parallel and concurrent code. Creates *parsers*, *compilers and interpreters* for new mini-languages. >50 languages.

Web technologies: Full stack web and cloud development using *GCP* and *AWS*; *MySQL*, *NoSQL*, *ElasticSearch*, *Redis*, *CouchDB*, *React*, *Angular*, *jQuery*, *Webpack*, *npm/yarn*, *Docker*, *Kubernetes*, *SRE*.

Team process and systems engineering: Designs build systems and cloud apps, and procedures for the problem and the team, some of which have been battle-tested for six years and are still going strong.

Security and privacy: Catches potential attack vectors at code review. Protects coworkers' and customers' privacy as a matter of deep personal conviction to "do no harm," while allowing the power and flexibility to get the job done, and done well.

Algorithms and Data Structures: *MaxMSP music synthesis and analysis, robot control, machine learning, OCR, pathfinding, 3D graphics and raytracing, operating systems*

Continuous Integration Testing: Jenkins, TravisCI, CircleCI

Other: Uses Arch Linux as daily driver. This resume was written in vim using Markdown and rendered with a Makefile.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cloud Software Engineer, Evernote (June 2016 - February 2023; Redwood City, CA four years; then remote in Phoenix, AZ)

Led the re-architecting and migration of <u>evernote.com</u> from PHP with AWS to Go with Google App Engine: My system design has been in production for six years so far. Recursive component template system; 26-language localization system; CMS integration for non-programmer edits to site; tooling for deploy, preview, unit test, and code quality; query tools to answer high-level questions about the web service. *Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Ubuntu, Debian and Alpine Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, git, Go/Golang, C#, Perl, PHP, Java, bash, dash, zsh, Python, MySQL, NoSQL, Redis, JavaScript/Node.js, Jenkins CI, webpack, React, yarn/npm, SASS, awk, grep, sed, jq, SRE*

Content Delivery Network (CDN): For images in Iterable emails. Google Cloud Storage

Browser-based note editor and checkout flow: Typescript, React, Java

Google Cloud Platform: load balancing, scaling, hosting, URL routing and event routing. *App Engine, Cloud Functions, Cloud Storage, Pub/Sub, StackDriver, BigQuery, KMS secrets management, HAProxy*

Communication: Slack (+ API), Atlassian JIRA and Confluence, BitBucket, DataDog, PagerDuty

Software Engineer, Coupa Software (May 2015 – January 2016; San Mateo, CA)

Optimized RSpec test harness to work 30% faster; in-browser integration tests and unit tests; cooperated via Agile with hundreds of developers using GitHub and Atlassian JIRA. *Ruby on Rails, RSpec, MySQL and migrations, Turnip unit tests, Jenkins, bash, JIRA*

Software Engineer Intern, Rustici Software (June 2014 - August 2014; Nashville, TN)

Released open-source Python client library for TinCan API (xAPI 2.0) and created a JSON object verifier and recognizer using JSON Schema and Node.js/JavaScript.

Industrial Controls Engineer, Bridgestone (May 2012 - December 2012; Nashville, TN)

Designed fail-safes, safety and control systems for factory machinery. *Embedded systems, RTOS, electrical schematics, AutoCAD Electrical (incl. plugin development in C# .Net, Visual Basic .Net, and AutoLISP), CoDeSys, RSLogix, PLC, structured text a.k.a. IEC 61131-3, ladder logic*

Computer Programmer Intern, Oak Ridge National Laboratory Physics Division (June 2010 - August 2010; Oak Ridge, TN)

Modernized a browser-based experiment log system. *PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, TinyMCE, ssh, vim, Red Hat Linux*

NOTABLE PERSONAL AND SCHOOL PROJECTS

- **github.com/chaimleib/intervaltree**, 2014 onward. Modify and query intervals in logarithmic time in pure Python 2/3. This is the industry reference implementation of interval trees in Python, cited in numerous academic research papers for genome research, computer vision applications, etc. *Python, data structures, open source, GitHub*
- github.com/chaimleib/dotfiles, 2014 onward. Portable, multi-OS environment setup scripts and automatic installers. bash, dash, zsh, busybox, Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, Mint, Arch, Alpine, Red Hat), POSIX, Solaris, CentOS, macOS, MinGW, vim/neovim script, Language Server Protocol
- **github.com/chaimleib/rpn**, 2023 onward. Calculator project to teach compiler tools. *C, flex, bison, parsers, compilers, interpreters, CircleCI, SonarCloud*
- **Pyenv v2.3.14,** github.com/pyenv/pyenv February 2023. Added patches for Python's source code, versions 3.6 and 3.5, fixing for the world compilation for modern OSes on x86_64 and Apple M1 processors. *C, patchfiles, GitHub, pyenv, Python, open-source*
- **Completed Linux From Scratch** twice, in 2006 and 2021 (<u>linuxfromscratch.org/lfs</u>). Compiled and configured a complete OS from C/C++ source code. *Linux*, OS, *boot sequence*, *bash*, *Makefile*, *X11*
- <u>chaimleib.com</u> personal website and jQuery audio player (zichronos), 2014 onward. TLS/HTTPS, Ruby, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Jekyll, GitHub Pages, GitHub Actions, bash, SCSS
- **USB Nintendo 64 Cartridge reader**, 2014. Allows backups of N64 games to the computer using Atmega32u4 (Teensy 1.0). *Embedded systems*, *C*, *Atmel microcontrollers*, *USB protocol*, *Linux device development*
- **2-axis gimballed spotlight with IR camera target tracker**, UC Berkeley EECS 149 Intro to Embedded Systems, 2014. *Embedded systems, C, Python, FSM program architecture, Raspberry Pi, Bluetooth, Nintendo Wii controller, RS485 serial servos*
- **Handwritten digit recognizer**, Coursera.com Machine Learning, August 2012 with Prof. Andrew Ng. *Octave (open-source clone of Matlab)*, *computer vision, directed machine learning, matrix algebra*
- **Lua-like interpreter, parser generator and bytecode compiler**, UC Berkeley CS 164 Compilers, 2010. *Python 2, compilers, parsers, interpreters, vimscript, vim syntax highlighting*

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley – B.S. program in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (August 2008 - March 2014)

Projects were completed in *Python*, *C*, *C*++, *Java*, *JavaScript*, *GNU Makefile*, *Matlab*, *Scheme*, *Verilog*, *and Latex*. Courses covered *physics*, *calculus*, *matrix algebra*, *recursive data structures and algorithms*, *AI*, *computer graphics*, *compilers*, *embedded systems*, *DSP*, *FPGAs*, *analog and digital circuits*.